A mother and daughter in Kentucky have
turned down a $26 million offer for part
of their farmland. CBS News' Jarod
Tatcher met with this family and asked
them why they said no to this massive
amount of money.
This is the land in rural Kentucky that
Delcia and her mother Ida turned down
$26 million for. I just said my land is
not for sale. I never had a for sale
sign on my land. I never wanted to sell
my land. Never even dreamed of thinking
about selling my land.
And it's priceless. It's easy to say no
to $26 million whenever it really
doesn't buy anything that you need.
Uh
Once this land is gone, um there
wouldn't be anything else I'd really
want. And they told me it wasn't a
difficult decision and it's one they'd
make again because this property isn't
just property. It's a home and it's a
lifestyle of farming that's been passed
down in generations and generations of
their family. Oh, it's all time where we
had
uh
parties, we would fix that back there
for the grandkids to have, you know,
cookouts.
Just every Christmas and everything we
needed it was usually right here.
They were offered tens of thousands of
dollars per acre as were a few of their
neighbors so that an unnamed company
could build a 2,000-plus acre data
center. It would be the biggest project
in the state.
>> Most of the people are
I've been around.
Please don't let us down. Please.
We Our land won't Our Our businesses
will be destroyed here. Our Our uh
homes will be
no value to them left. Please don't let
this happen to our county. A community
group called We Are Mason County is
suing to try and slow down the process
and learn who the organization is, the
company is, behind the project.
I cannot get enough of these ladies.
>> so great. And Jarod Tatcher joins us
now. This is such There are few stories
that kind of are refreshing in a way
that people will act in ways that you
don't expect. $26 million,
were they offered that for all of their
land or just part of it? Cuz they could
have kept some of the land probably.
>> Right. So, between Delcia and Ida, the
mother and daughter, they own around 600
acres and with more of their family it's
over a thousand. So, they were offered
this money for part of their land and as
you heard they said no.
Wow. So, tell us about this lawsuit the
that was filed by the community groups
to slow this development. So, there's a
citizen community group called We Are
Mason County and just this week they
filed this lawsuit and 30 minutes ago
the leader of the group sent me a copy
of the complaint. And basically what
they're arguing is that nowhere in the
county zoning ordinance does it say
anything about data centers. So, they're
arguing that if this were to go through,
if the construction were to go through,
it would be an illegal construction
project. And their goal here is to
square that out and also to slow this
process down and figure out who this
anonymous builder is behind it. I mean,
if it's a data center, my mind is going
to all of the Silicon Valley companies
that we know by name. I won't name them,
but it's probably one of those. And the
lawyer who is representing the citizen
group is saying and at this community
meeting I went to on Wednesday, he was
saying exactly that. He's like, "We need
to know who they are. I have a right as
the attorney representing people in this
community to cross-examine the company
behind it."
>> able to represent them fairly.
But I love though about this story is
that these women are digging their heels
to try to preserve a way of life that is
being threatened by the future, by
technology, by the needs of our cell
phones, right? Data centers are needed
to support all of the uses of our cell
phones and that the community is even
coming together and rejecting this
money. Right. So, the two things I want
to point out there, a lawyer for the
project said, "Hey, you guys all have
cell phones. You need data centers like
this in order for them to operate." And
also the community coming together.
While people like Ida and Delcia did
receive
offers for their property that are many
times more than what the land is
actually worth, a lot of neighbors did
not. They didn't receive any offers of
compensation and they told me that
they're concerned that if this project
were to go through, the value of their
property, their home,
>> will plummet. And they're also concerned
about the possibility of the project
being an eyesore, of noise and sound and
possible environmental pollution. All of
those things it's going to They're going
to need employees to operate those data
centers. I also just love their little
quote uh which is What was it? Like It
really doesn't buy anything that you
need. All that money.
>> Yeah. I mean, that was beautiful.
>> So, and I asked them, you know, like fun
question we always ask our friends, if
you were to win the lottery, what would
you do with the money? I asked them
that, you know.
>> Yeah. You kind of were offered a crazy
sum of money. What would you do with it?
They said, "I would buy more land and
more cows." I love these American women.
>> Jarod, awesome story, man. Thank you
very much. That's really great.